LYNN FIFER, JR.

2325 Montezuma Drive, Unit D Florissant, MO 63031 \cdot 314-479-6069

lynn.fiferjr@gmail.com

Burgeoning IT professional and software engineer with extensive experience in customer-facing interactions and some experience in Object Oriented Programming and a solid base of computer hardware knowledge. After being a stay-at-home parent for the majority of the past two years, I'm ready to re-join the workforce in the pursuit of a fulfilling career in tech. Eager to join the IT field with similarly passionate professionals to meet performance goals within an organization and to further develop my skills as a software engineer.

CORE PROFICIENCIES

CUSTOMER SERVICE

- Effective communicator
- Skilled at arbitration and conflict resolution
 - Empathetic
- Attentive to verbal and nonverbal communication
 - Adaptable and decisive

TIME MANAGEMENT

- Sets goals and specific calls to action
 - Organizational and planning skills
- Familiar with scheduling applications
 - Works with a sense of urgency
 - Emphasis on punctuality
 - Delegates tasks by proficiency

TEAMWORK

- Customer Service skills overlap (conflict resolution, empathy, communication)
 - Receptive to constructive criticism
 - Experienced in small and large group collaboration
 - Transparent and open towards teammates
 - Accountability for self and team

ATTENTION TO DETAIL

- Active listener
- Quality as a focal point
 - Critical thinker
- Persistent and thorough

EXPERIENCE

JUNE 2016 – NOVEMBER 2018, JULY 2021 - AUGUST 2021 CUSTOMER SERVICE ASSOCIATE, WALMART

Collaborated with others in small and large group settings to create optimal customer experience, used critical thinking and problem-solving skills to resolve customer and employer issues, and led and supported others in conflict resolution while operating with urgency.

MARCH 2014 - MAY 2016

PREP COOK, BOEHRINGER-INGELHEIM VETMEDICA

Small group environment using active listening skills, being thorough and transparent, setting and meeting time-based goals, planning routines and adapting to changes in and availability of ingredients.

EDUCATION

AUGUST 2012 - JUNE 2015

COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSYTEMS (INCOMPLETE), MISSOURI WESTERN STATE UNIVERSITY

Completed coursework: Applications in Computer Technology 101, Java 101

MAY 2008

GENERAL STUDIES, UNIVERSITY CITY HIGH SCHOOL

ACTIVITIES

Passionate about gaming in particular and tech in general. While I've been a gamer since age 4, my first foray into programming was when I attempted to teach myself BASIC junior year in high school. Coding was something that always drew me in, eventually going to college to try to make it my career. Recently, my focus has been to get into tech any way I can starting with working towards COMPTIA A+ certification.